

FRANCISCO PINTO SANTOS

Senior full-stack developer | R&D Engineer | Researcher | Associate Professor at UPSA

3-07-1998

J +34 636 627 009 in franpintosantos

Salamanca, Spain franpintosantos@gmail.com

gandalfran

0000-0002-9500-9336

INTERESTS

Full-stack web developement

Web scraping

Software engenieering

Continuous Integration

Code Generation

SKILLS

Node.js Express.js Vue.js

SQL DB TypeScript |

NoSQL DB

Spring Boot Java

Apache Kafka Python

Flask

Git | AWS GitHub Actions

Docker

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native

English: Full professional competence

ABOUT ME

Senior full-stack developer & Researcher & Team Lead at BISITE research group | Research collaborator at AIR Institute | Lecturer at UPSA. My interests include full-stack web application development, Apache Kafka-based systems design and implementation and code generation.

EXPERIENCE

Lecturer | Pontifical University of Salamanca

1 02/2022 - 09/2022

Salamanca, España

Senior full-stack developer & Team lead | BISITE Research Group

iii 01/2022 - present

Salamanca, Spain

- Coordination of planning, design and development of R&D projects within a small team (5-10 people).
- Code-generation system design and implementation for agile project development.
- Design and implementation of a human resources management application for the company.
- API rest development Python Flask-restx.
- Development of web scrapers and web crawlers.
- Web applications development with Vue.js, Node.js, Express.js and TypeScript.
- Design and development of ETL systems via Apache Kafka.
- Implementation of continuous integration systems with GitHub Actions.

Senior full-stack developer & Team lead assistant | BISITE Research Group

i 09/2020 - 12/2021

Salamanca, Spain

- Assistant in the coordination of planning, design and development of R&D projects.
- Complete development of the deepint Python package.
- API rest development Python Flask-restx.
- Development of web scrapers and web crawlers.
- Web applications development with Vue.js, Node.js, Express.js and TypeScript.
- Design and development of ETL systems via Apache Kafka.
- Implementation of continuous integration systems with GitHub Actions.

Full-stack developer | BISITE Research Group

= 09/2019 - 09/2020

Salamanca, Spain

- Development of web scrapers and web crawlers.
- API rest Development in Java Spring Boot and Python Flask-restx.
- Web applications development with Vue.is, Node.is, Express.is and TypeScript.
- Design and development of ETL systems via Apache Kafka.
- Implementation of continuous integration systems with GitHub Actions.

Intern student during summer | BISITE Research Group

6 06/2018 - 09/2018

- Salamanca, Spain
- API rest Development in Java Spring Boot.

- Web development with Vue.js and Webpack.
- Development of web scrapers and web crawlers.
- Design and development of ETL systems via Apache Kafka.

Intern student during summer | BISITE Research Group

i 06/2017 - 09/2017

- Salamanca, Spain
- API rest Development in Java EE and Java Spring Boot.
- Web development with Vue.js and Webpack.

EDUCATION

Master in Smart Cities & Intelligent buildings | University of Salamanca

= 09/2021 - 09/2022

Salamanca, Spain

Master in software engineering | University of Salamanca

i 09/2020 - 09/2022

Salamanca, Spain

- GPA: 9.41
- Beneficiary of the academic excellence scholarship from the University of Salamanca.

Degree in computer science | University of Salamanca

1 09/2016 - 07/2020

Salamanca, Spain

- GPA: 9.55
- Graduated as first of the promotion 2016-2020 with double end of studies award, granted by the University of Salamanca and the Faculty of Sciences of the same university.
- 25 calcifications with honors, including the end-of-degree project-
- Beneficiary of the scholarship for collaboration with department for the 2019-2020 academic course.
- Award to the third-best academic record of the 2016-2020 promotion at national level in the field of engineering by SEDEA.
- Student representation activities for three years.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Awarded to one of the best academic records of the 2016-2020 graduating class of the Faculty of Sciences of the University of Salamanca.

11/2021 | Salamanca, Spain

Award for the best academic record of the 2016-2020 promotion of the Degree in Computer Science of the University of Salamanca.

07/2021 | Salamanca, Spain

Third at the national ranking of Spain degree students by SEDEA. 07/2021 | Salamanca, Spain

Member of one of the two finalist teams of the AWS hackathon organized by Viewnext IBM.

02/2020 | Salamanca, Spain

Placed as first team of Salamanca, on Google Hashcode on Everis Salamanca Hub.

02/2020 | Salamanca, Spain

Member of the winning team of the Blockchain hackathon organized by the DIGITEC project.

10/2019 | Salamanca, Spain

Member of the finalist team (Global Nominee) in the NASA Space Apps Challenge hackathon at the Everis Salamanca hub.

10/2019 | Salamanca, Spain

Member of the winning team of the smart speaker hackathon organized by Viewnext.

02/2019 | Salamanca, Spain